PRODUCT MANAGER

Professional Background

Health Information Management professional for 34 years with experience in Natural Language Processing technologies, Product Management, Agile Software Development, and Strategic Business Development. Accomplished, goal-oriented healthcare professional who leverages holistic experience. Proven success leading product development and marketing to promote health information management applications such as Computer-Assisted Coding and Clinical Documentation Improvement on platform utilizing NLP technologies.

Experienced Consultant, certified as an RHIT, CCDS, and an AHIMA-approved ICD-10-CM/PCS trainer, with Product Management and Marketing experience in health information management and NLP (Natural Language Processing) technologies.

Skill Highlights

- Extensive Coding and Clinical Documentation Improvement experience with credentials.
- Strong Product Management experience with NLP (Natural Language Processing), Computer-Assisted Coding, Clinical Documentation Improvement products and deidentification software.
- Agile software development trained
- Content Development for NLP experience with SNOMED and terminology mapping.
- Business development experience

Accomplishments

- Create and manage product road maps and plans for various products including NLP content development and computer-assisted coding
- Managed team of content developers for NLP-enabled products
- Developed vision for health information management technologies
- Managed products from conception to new product launch, implementation and user acceptance
- Created product marketing strategies
- Project management

Professional Experience

Product Manager 01/2008 to Current Wex Inc. South Portland, ME

- Developed and executed product road map for computer-assisted coding
- Participated in requirements, design review for computer-assisted coding, clinical document improvement, and coding/CDI work flow management applications
- Involved in product development agile cycle from inception to product launch, implementation and user acceptance.
- Developed and executed content development road map to support NLP-enabled product strategy
- Participated in the creation of product marketing strategy and sales collateral
- Business writing to include strategic growth documents for product line as well as business plans
- Served as thought leader and authored various white papers on topics including computer-assisted coding, natural language processing technology, and ICD-10 transition

Owner and Consultant 01/2006 to Current Computacenter Plc Westwood, MA

• Independent consultant specializing in Health Information Management business operations and technologies; Natural Language Processing technologies; Product Management; Project Management; Business Development and Market Research

Consultant 11/2006 to 11/2010 De-ID Data Corp City, STATE

- De-identification software implementations
- Account management
- Oversight on marketing communications
- Market research
- Business development

Siemens 01/2006 to 01/2010 Artificial Medical Intelligence

Education and Training

CCDS Credential: Clinical Documentation Improvement 2014 Association of Clinical Documentation Improvement Specialists

AHIMA Approved ICD-10-CM & PCS Trainer: ICD-10-CM and ICD-10-PCS 2013 American Health Information Management Association Bachelor of Science 1990 University of Pittsburgh

RHIT Certification: Health Information Management 1987 American Health Information Management Association

Certifications

- RHIT (Registered Health Information Technician), AHIMA
- CCDS (Clinical Documentation Improvement Specialist), Association of Clinical Documentation Improvement Specialists

• AHIMA-Approved ICD-10-CM and ICD-10-PCS Trainer

Affiliations

- AHIMA (American Health Information Management Association)
- PHIMA (Pennsylvania Health Information Management Association)
- WPHIMA (Western PA Health Information Management Association
- ACDIS (Association of Clinical Documentation Improvement Specialists)

Publications

- White Paper Author, "The Silent Killer" (Precyse) (Poor documentation and its impact on NLP and analytics)
- White Paper Author, "Stay the Course: Trust Innovation to Guide Your ICD-10 Transition"
- Article Author, "Transition Easier with Technology-Driven Coding Tools" (AHIMA ICD-TEN, May 15, 2010)
- Article Author, "Computer-Assisted Coding for Inpatient" (For The Record, November 26, 2007) CAC: It's Not Just for Outpatient"
- Accuro Health Newsletter, "Coding Focus News", Jan/Feb 2008 edition
- Authored Cover Story for ADVANCE for Health Information Professionals, March 18, 2002; "Transcription Outsourcing: Is It the Clear Winner?"

Skills

Technical Skills:

- Windows
- OSX
- Microsoft/Mac Word, Excel, OneNote, PowerPoint, Outlook, Visio, Microsoft Visual Studio
- MindMap
- TruCode/3M encoders;
- SKYPE and other remote meeting tools such as GoToMeeting

Business Writing Skills:

- Business plans
- Strategic growth documents
- Marketing collateral
- While Papers
- PowerPoint presentations for public speaking
- Product Roadmaps